Postdoctoral researcher Aviz - INRIA

Overview

I am a researcher in the field of visual analytics, a practice that brings together data analysis, information visualization, HCI methods and software development. My research focus is on network visual analysis, for which I developed analysis methods for large datasets and interactive prototypes using web technologies. I have presented my work at IEEE VIS, Eurovis, and I have publications in IEEE Transactions on Visualization & Computer Graphics, the top visualization journal.

Professionally used technologies

Python	Jupyter	JavaScript	Dart	React	Git
Pandas	NumPy	D3	Mapbox-GL	Redux	C/C++
Scikit-Learn	R	WebGL	Web canvas	Angular	Matlab

Professional experience

Postdoctoral Researcher

INRIA Saclay

France

Jun 2018 - present

- Prototype for visualizing dynamic hypergraphs with focus on usability. Technologies: Dart, Web canvas and Python.
- Development of a prototype for analysis of multidimensional projections for large datasets. Technologies: JavaScript, WebGl, D3, Python, Flask, Scikit-Learn, Pandas, SciPy.
- Currently working in the design of a mixed-initiative prototype for dynamic network clustering visualization for large datasets.

Researcher Consultant

Visibilia

Brazil Dec 2018 - Jul 2019

 Prototype for visualizing recommendation of business regions. Technologies: JavaScript, React, MapGl, D3 and Python.

Visiting PhD Student

INRIA Saclay

France Aug 2016 - Jul 2017

Visiting PhD Student
New York University

USA Nov 2015

Software Developer Peru Credit Bank (BCP) Peru Aug 2010 - Jul 2011

EDUCATION

University of São Paulo

Ph.D. Computer Science

Brazil

Dec 2013 - May 2018

Dissertation title: Graph signal processing for visual analysis and data exploration.

- Network and spatio-temporal data analysis using graph signal processing.
- Technologies: Python, Pandas, Matlab, JavaScript, React, D3, Angular.
- Relevant courses: Machine learning, mathematical tools for data analysis and data clustering.

University of São Paulo

Brazil

M.Sc. Computer Science

Aug 2011 - Nov 2013

Thesis title: Normal correction towards smoothing point-based surfaces.

San Pablo Catholic University

Peru

B.S. Informatics Engineering (Computer Science)

2005 - 2010

Coursework project: Fluid simulation using SPH, Computer graphics.

- top student in class

EXPERTISE

visual analytics network visualization data science graph signal processing

> paola.valdivia@inria.fr +33 06 25938033

http://www.aviz.fr/~paola

paolavaldivia 🕥

paolavaldivia **in**

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

spanish native
english advanced
portuguese intermediate
french basic

REFERENCES

Dr. Jean Daniel Fekete

AVIZ Team Leader INRIA Saclay Jean-Daniel.Fekete@inria.fr +55163373-9697

Dr. Luis Gustavo Nonato

Full Professor University of Sao Paulo gnonato@icmc.usp.br +55(16)3373-9697

Dr. Catherine Plaisant

Senior Research Scientist *University of Maryland* plaisant@cs.umd.edu +1 (301) 405-2768

- Valdivia, P., Buono, P., Plaisant C., Dufournaud N. and Fekete, J.-D. (2020). *Analyzing Dynamic Hypergraphs with Parallel Aggregated Ordered Hypergraph Visualization*. To appear in IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics.
- Valdivia, P., Dias, F., Petronetto, F., Silva, C. T., and Nonato, L. G. (2015). Wavelet-based visualization of time-varying data on graphs. In Visual Analytics Science and Technology (VAST), 2015 IEEE Conference.
- Col, A. D., Valdivia, P., Petronetto, F., Dias, F., Silva, C. T., and Nonato, L. G. (2017). Wavelet-based visual analysis of dynamic networks. IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics.
- Col, A. D., Valdivia, P., Petronetto, F., Dias, F., Silva, C. T., and Nonato, L. G. (2017). Wavelet-based visual analysis for data exploration. Computing in Science Engineering.
- Søren Knudsen, Jan Aerts, Daniel Archambault, Remco Chang, Jean-Daniel Fekete, **Valdivia**, **P.** et al. (2019) *Unifying the framework of Multi-Layer Network and Visual Analytics. Visual Analytics of Multilayer Networks Across Disciplines*, Dagstuhl Reports.
- Dias, F., Mansour, M. R., Valdivia, P., Cousty, J., and Najman, L. (2017). *Watersheds on Hypergraphs for Data Clustering*. In International Symposium on Mathematical Morphology and Its Applications to Signal and Image Processing. Springer, Cham.
- Ferreira, V., Valejo, A., Valdivia, P. and Valverde-Rebaza, J. (2019) *Exploiting Geographical Data to improve Recommender Systems for Business Opportunities in Urban Areas*. To appear in Proceedings of BRACIS 2019.
- Dias, M.D, Valdivia, P., Petronetto, F., Nonato, L. G. (2013). *Graph Spectral Filtering for Network Simplification*. In Graphics, Patterns and Images (SIBGRAPI), 2013 26th SIBGRAPI-Conference. IEEE.
- Valdivia, P., Cedrim, D., Petronetto, F., Paiva, A., and Nonato, L. G. (2013). *Normal Correction towards Smoothing Point-Based Surfaces*. In Graphics, Patterns and Images (SIBGRAPI), 2013 26th SIBGRAPI-Conference. IEEE.

SHORT PAPERS

• **Valdivia, P.**, Buono, P., Plaisant C., Dufournaud N. and Fekete, J.-D. (2018). *Using Dynamic Hypergraphs to Reveal the Evolution of the Business Network of a 17th Century French Woman Merchant*. VIS 2018-3rd Workshop on Visualization for the Digital Humanities.

Posters

- **Valdivia, P.**, Buono, P., and Fekete, J.-D. (2017). *Hypenet: Visualizing Dynamic Hypergraphs*. In Puig, A. P. and Isenberg, T., editors, EuroVis 2017 Posters. The Eurographics Association.
- Dimara, E., **Valdivia, P.**, and Kinkeldey, C. (2017). *DcPAIRS: A Pairs Plot Based Decision Support System*. In Puig, A. P. and Isenberg, T., editors, EuroVis 2017 Posters. The Eurographics Association.

SOFTWARE PROTOTYPES AND CONTRIBUTIONS

• Paohvis. Prototype for visualizing dynamic hypergraphs.

Implemented in Dart using web canvas. Available at: http://www.aviz.fr/paohvis/

• **Waviz**. Prototype for analyzing spatio-temporal data based on the graph wavelet transform. Implemented in JavaScript using D3.

Available at: https://paolavaldivia.github.io/waviz/

• **Siion**. Prototype for showing the best potential regions for opening a business in the city of São Paulo. Implemented in Javascript using Mapbox Available at: http://siion.visibilia.net.br

• **Dynamic Network Explorer**. Prototype for analyzing dynamic networks based on the graph wavelet transform. Implemented in JavaScript using the framework AngularJS and D3.

Available at: https://paolavaldivia.github.io/dynnet_wavelet/

• **Networkcube**. Improvement of the matrix visualization of networks in this system. Implemented in Typescript using WebGL and D3.

Available at: http://networkcube.net/